

# Ashish Sinha

Senior Data Engineer

Ashishsinha1504@gmail.com

+353 089 407 3896

Limerick

15 April 1993

https://ash1504.github.io/ashish15/

Data Engineer and RPA Developer with 5+ years experience in the IT software industry. Demonstrated excellent skills developing integrated processes in Azure Databricks, Data Factory, Informatica, and automating tasks using UiPath RPA tool, PowerShell, and Python. Experience with different other Azure services such as Azure Synapse, Logic Apps, Power Automate to name a few, True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# ETL/RPA Developer Saama Technologies/BeiGene

10/2020 - 06/2021,

Pune

Focused on developing molecularly targeted and immuno-oncology drug candidates for the treatment of cancer.

- Developed and automated the ETL processes to load data into Synapse using Azure Data Factory and Databricks, leveraging the PowerShell and Python scripts to communicate with Azure services from on-premises file system.
- Developed/Optimized workflows for Quality Analytics using UiPath and Python.
- Automated processes to move file to or from FTP server and to upload/download files from SharePoint using UiPath RPA.
- Automated processes to download file from mail and process them to Database using UiPath RPA.
- Automated sending job notification with run details of each process thus minimized the monitoring and debugging time.

Contact: Shweta Barhate (Team Lead) - shweta.barhate@saama.com

# **RPA Developer**

# Saama Technologies/Portola Pharmaceuticals

07/2019 - 09/2020.

Research develops and commercializes drugs focusing primarily on the treatment of thrombosis and hematological malignancies.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Pull data from Salesforce through dynamic queries and integrate it with SQL Server using UiPath thus saving Monthly recurring \$100 licensing costs.
- Integrated with BOX using API to upload/download files for further processing thus saving manual efforts and time.
- FTP operations were integrated by RPA eliminated Dell Boomi and saved annual recurring \$100k licensing cost.
- Automate download of Files from web portals where we login into web portals, download files, do quality checks and pass file for further processing.

Contact: Deepali Desai - deepali.desai@saama.com

# Informatica Developer Infosys Ltd./Stater

01/2017 - 12/2019.

Pune

Provides mortgage services and platforms for external money lenders.

# Achievements/Tasks

- Develop mappings according to the client's need
- Automation of adding columns to existing's mappings using PowerShell scripts

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Technology** SRM University/ Chennai

08/2012 - 05/2016,

Courses

Flectronics and Communication Engineering

# SKILLS

Azure Synapse Azure Data Factory PowerShell **Databricks UiPath RPA** Data Science Python **SQL** Server Informatica Google Dialogflow

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Shining Star of the Month (08/2020)

Awarded for work on UiPath and Google dialogue flow chatbots

Shining Star of the Month (01/2020)

Shining Star of the Month for automating download of files from the portal and upload/download files from BOX using REST API and Box Connector in UiPath

# CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning (08/2020 - Present)

Completed certification on Machine Learning from SimpliLearn.

Data Science with Python (07/2020 - Present)

Completed certification on Data Science with Python from SimpliLearn.

UiPath Al Fabric Overview (07/2020 - Present)

RPA Developer Foundation Diploma Certification (05/2020 - Present)

Completed Developer foundation certification from UiPath.

UiPath Advanced RPA Developer Diploma Certification (05/2020 - Present)

Completed Advanced Developer foundation certification from UiPath.

# ORGANIZATIONS

Saama Technologies (01/2019 - Present)

Software Engineer

Infosys Limited (06/2016 - 12/2019)

Senior System Engineer